<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/" xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/" version="2.0">

<channel>
	<title>Children of Conservation</title>
	<atom:link href="https://childrenofconservation.org/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
	<link>https://childrenofconservation.org/</link>
	<description>Protecting African Wildlife by Strengthening Communities</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Sep 2023 20:13:32 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.7.3</generator>

<image>
	<url>https://childrenofconservation.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/04/cropped-COC-Long-Ways-1-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Children of Conservation</title>
	<link>https://childrenofconservation.org/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Dr. Jane Goodall awards co-founder Lifetime Achievement!</title>
		<link>https://childrenofconservation.org/kerry-wins/</link>
					<comments>https://childrenofconservation.org/kerry-wins/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator>
  <![CDATA[lorna]]>
</dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2023 20:56:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category>
<![CDATA[Recognition]]>
</category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://childrenofconservation.org/?p=3473</guid>

					<description>
<![CDATA[<p>Children of Conservation co-founder Kerry Stumpe recently received Ngamba Island Chimpanzee Sanctuary's Lifetime Achievement Award from Dr. Jane Goodall during its 25th Anniversary Gala in Kampala, Uganda. This award recognized Stumpe and CofC for their continued efforts to improve the lives of animals, workers and children involved in conservation over the past 20 years. <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6rQBIeeJuk0" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Click here for highlight video</a>
</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://childrenofconservation.org/kerry-wins/">Dr. Jane Goodall awards co-founder Lifetime Achievement!</a> appeared first on <a href="https://childrenofconservation.org">Children of Conservation</a>.</p>
]]>
</description>
										<content:encoded>
<![CDATA[<p>Children of Conservation co-founder Kerry Stumpe recently received Ngamba Island Chimpanzee Sanctuary’s Lifetime Achievement Award from Dr. Jane Goodall during its 25th Anniversary Gala in Kampala, Uganda. This award recognized Stumpe and CofC for their continued efforts to improve the lives of animals, workers and children involved in conservation over the past 20 years.</p>











<img src="https://childrenofconservation.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/JANE-GOODALL-AWARD-SOCIAL-MEDIA.png">



<p>
</p>




<a class="wp-block-button__link has-vivid-green-cyan-background-color has-background wp-element-button" href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6rQBIeeJuk0" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">View Highlight Video of Kerry &amp; CofC’s continued efforts.</a>




<p>
</p>



<p>
</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://childrenofconservation.org/kerry-wins/">Dr. Jane Goodall awards co-founder Lifetime Achievement!</a> appeared first on <a href="https://childrenofconservation.org">Children of Conservation</a>.</p>]]>
</content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://childrenofconservation.org/kerry-wins/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Read All About It! Children of Conservation featured in TravelEssence Magazine</title>
		<link>https://childrenofconservation.org/read-all-about-it-children-of-conservation-featured-in-travelessence-magazine/</link>
					<comments>https://childrenofconservation.org/read-all-about-it-children-of-conservation-featured-in-travelessence-magazine/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator>
<![CDATA[lorna]]>
</dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 20 Jul 2021 17:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category>
<![CDATA[Uncategorized]]>
</category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://childrenofconservation.org/?p=2840</guid>

					<description>
<![CDATA[<p>Children of Conservation founder Kerry, and board member, Mike are featured in this month&#8217;s edition of TravelEssence Magazine. The two eco-heroes are acknowledged for their incredible work helping to build gabions to protect the shoreline of Ngamba Island Chimapanzee Sanctuary from catastrophic rising water levels due to global warming. You can read the article in&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://childrenofconservation.org/read-all-about-it-children-of-conservation-featured-in-travelessence-magazine/">Read All About It! Children of Conservation featured in TravelEssence Magazine</a> appeared first on <a href="https://childrenofconservation.org">Children of Conservation</a>.</p>
]]>
</description>
										<content:encoded>
<![CDATA[<p>Children of Conservation founder Kerry, and board member, Mike are featured in this month’s edition of TravelEssence Magazine. The two eco-heroes are acknowledged for their incredible work helping to build gabions to protect the shoreline of Ngamba Island Chimapanzee Sanctuary from catastrophic rising water levels due to global warming.</p>



<img src="https://childrenofconservation.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Screen-Shot-2021-05-30-at-10.36.33-AM.png">



<p>You can read the article in TravelEssence Magazine, read across the world by passionate travelers, here.</p>




<a class="wp-block-button__link has-vivid-green-cyan-background-color has-background" href="https://www.travelessencemag.com" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Read the article in TravelEssence Magazine here</a>




<a href="https://ea586b15-e49f-4cd5-aeb6-1df0b780387f.filesusr.com/ugd/da2976_98bd6cacad9249b4a10e94bb5089c1dd.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">
<img src="https://childrenofconservation.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/05/Screen-Shot-2021-05-30-at-10.37.04-AM.png">
</a>
<p>The post <a href="https://childrenofconservation.org/read-all-about-it-children-of-conservation-featured-in-travelessence-magazine/">Read All About It! Children of Conservation featured in TravelEssence Magazine</a> appeared first on <a href="https://childrenofconservation.org">Children of Conservation</a>.</p>]]>
</content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://childrenofconservation.org/read-all-about-it-children-of-conservation-featured-in-travelessence-magazine/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Private: Give a little extra love this Valentine’s Day</title>
		<link>https://childrenofconservation.org/give-a-little-extra-love-this-valentines-day/</link>
					<comments>https://childrenofconservation.org/give-a-little-extra-love-this-valentines-day/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator>
<![CDATA[lorna]]>
</dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2021 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category>
<![CDATA[Uncategorized]]>
</category>
		<category>
<![CDATA[Valentine&#039;s Day]]>
</category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://childrenofconservation.org/?p=2616</guid>

					<description>
<![CDATA[<p>Give someone you love a special card this February 14th. You don&#8217;t even have to mail it! Buy a Valentine&#8217;s Day tribute card from Children of Conservation before February 10 and we will mail your card with a handwritten message from you. Each card represents a donation made in their honor and we will include&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://childrenofconservation.org/give-a-little-extra-love-this-valentines-day/">Private: Give a little extra love this Valentine&#8217;s Day</a> appeared first on <a href="https://childrenofconservation.org">Children of Conservation</a>.</p>
]]>
</description>
										<content:encoded>
<![CDATA[<p>Give someone you love a special card this February 14th.</p>



<p>You don’t even have to mail it!</p>



<p>
<strong>Buy a Valentine’s Day tribute card from Children of Conservation before February 10 and we will mail your card with a handwritten message from you.</strong>
<strong>
</strong>
</p>



<p>Each card represents a donation made in their honor and we will include a message letting them know that you’ve made a gift to children in Africa in their name.</p>



<p>Your Valentine will receive a beautiful card of your choice, featuring an animal-lovers elephant image or a photo of children in Myende, Uganda.</p>



<p>
<a href="https://childrenofconservation.z2systems.com/np/clients/childrenofconservation/donation.jsp?campaign=12&amp;&amp;secureIdCustomer=1&amp;">Just click here to go to the purchase page.</a> Fill out the form to tell us what you’d like us to write in the card and where we should mail it.</p>



<img src="https://childrenofconservation.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/Screen-Shot-2021-01-25-at-5.08.42-PM.png">
<p>The post <a href="https://childrenofconservation.org/give-a-little-extra-love-this-valentines-day/">Private: Give a little extra love this Valentine’s Day</a> appeared first on <a href="https://childrenofconservation.org">Children of Conservation</a>.</p>]]>
</content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://childrenofconservation.org/give-a-little-extra-love-this-valentines-day/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Kicking off 2021 with emergency construction in Uganda</title>
		<link>https://childrenofconservation.org/kicking-off-2021-with-emergency-construction-in-uganda/</link>
					<comments>https://childrenofconservation.org/kicking-off-2021-with-emergency-construction-in-uganda/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator>
<![CDATA[lorna]]>
</dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Jan 2021 01:36:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category>
<![CDATA[Uncategorized]]>
</category>
		<category>
<![CDATA[africa]]>
</category>
		<category>
<![CDATA[chimpanzees]]>
</category>
		<category>
<![CDATA[ecotourism]]>
</category>
		<category>
<![CDATA[Ngamba Island]]>
</category>
		<category>
<![CDATA[Uganda]]>
</category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://childrenofconservation.org/?p=2606</guid>

					<description>
<![CDATA[<p>The challenges of 2020 were not just limited to COVID-19 at Ngamba Chimpanzee Sanctuary in Uganda. The catastrophe of climate change came to their shores in the form of rising lake levels and uncontrollable flooding. Water levels shot up in 2020 and destroyed infrastructure, piers and eroded the delicate shoreline of the 100 acre island.&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://childrenofconservation.org/kicking-off-2021-with-emergency-construction-in-uganda/">Kicking off 2021 with emergency construction in Uganda</a> appeared first on <a href="https://childrenofconservation.org">Children of Conservation</a>.</p>
]]>
</description>
										<content:encoded>
<![CDATA[<p>The challenges of 2020 were not just limited to COVID-19 at Ngamba Chimpanzee Sanctuary in Uganda. The catastrophe of climate change came to their shores in the form of rising lake levels and uncontrollable flooding. Water levels shot up in 2020 and destroyed infrastructure, piers and eroded the delicate shoreline of the 100 acre island.</p>



<p>Ngamba is home to 50 rescued chimpanzees from cruelty situations around the world. These poor Great Apes have lived in circuses, traveling zoos, private homes, prison-like conditions and much worse. They are cared for at Ngamba Island by a team of expert primatologists and keepers and live freely in 99 acres of forest. The natural boundary of the lake keeps them on the island and they can roam free at night, making nests in the trees as they would in the wild, or come in to the safe, caged area of the island where they are offered broth before bed.</p>



<p>Children of Conservation has partnered with Ngamba Island to support their conservation work, community outreach and support for a decade and we knew we had to help when we heard the island was damaged. Board members Kerry and Mike traveled to Uganda this January to assist in the construction of ‘gabions’ in the water to protect the shoreline and prevent further damage. Below, you can see them working on the gabions in Lake Victoria with Ngamba Island staff.</p>



<img src="https://childrenofconservation.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/small-boat-work-1024x732.jpg">



<img src="https://childrenofconservation.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/small-Next-Gabion-moved-1024x731.jpg">



<img src="https://childrenofconservation.org/wp-content/uploads/2021/01/small-Rock-Line1-1024x732.jpg">



<p>This is Children of Conservation’s first project to address the devastating effects of a natural disaster due to climate change.  At its peak, Ngamba Island only rises 19 feet above the lake’s edge. Although it’s the second largest freshwater lake in the world, Victoria’s water level has risen a record 5 feet in the past year, claiming 30% of Ngamba Island’s shoreline. </p>



<p>Board member, Mike, says: “For much of the day, we’re working in chest high water, first positioning the gabions to assure they’re level and secure from the possible undertow. “</p>



<p>CofC founder, Kerry, says: “With each rock delivery, we line up in our human chain to transport the rocks one by one from the shore to the 4 guys at the gabion cages who carefully position the stones in the baskets.  Every 10 to 15 the “gabion guys” disappear beneath the water’s surface to install cross-wires, which have to be done every 8 inches to stabilize and secure the sides from buckling. Mike &amp; I revel in the securing of the crossties as it allows our 55 year old backs to rest for a bit.”</p>



<p>We are so proud of you, Kerry &amp; Mike! </p>
<p>The post <a href="https://childrenofconservation.org/kicking-off-2021-with-emergency-construction-in-uganda/">Kicking off 2021 with emergency construction in Uganda</a> appeared first on <a href="https://childrenofconservation.org">Children of Conservation</a>.</p>]]>
</content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://childrenofconservation.org/kicking-off-2021-with-emergency-construction-in-uganda/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Give the Gift of Hope this Holiday Season</title>
		<link>https://childrenofconservation.org/give-the-gift-of-hope-this-holiday-season/</link>
					<comments>https://childrenofconservation.org/give-the-gift-of-hope-this-holiday-season/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator>
<![CDATA[lorna]]>
</dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2020 21:49:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category>
<![CDATA[Uncategorized]]>
</category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://childrenofconservation.org/?p=2482</guid>

					<description>
<![CDATA[<p>This year has been so hard for so many people. We know you&#8217;ve been asked to give and give. We want to offer you the opportunity to give one last time for 2020 and make a difference to an individual in Africa that you can form a lasting bond with. Six students have been part&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://childrenofconservation.org/give-the-gift-of-hope-this-holiday-season/">Give the Gift of Hope this Holiday Season</a> appeared first on <a href="https://childrenofconservation.org">Children of Conservation</a>.</p>
]]>
</description>
										<content:encoded>
<![CDATA[<p>This year has been so hard for so many people. We know you’ve been asked to give and give. We want to offer you the opportunity to give one last time for 2020 and make a difference to an individual in Africa that you can form a lasting bond with.</p>



<p>Six students have been part of a Children of Conservation pilot program. Five years ago, they were nominated by their village chiefs, as part of an exchange program between conservationists and Kenyan villages that killed elephants to generate funds. We entered binding agreements with the village chiefs that they would no longer kill elephants if we provided the best education possible for their brightest kids.</p>



<p>So, for the past five years<span style="text-decoration: underline;"> ZERO elephants have been killed</span> by these communities and six smart young people attended great high schools. This summer they graduated and <strong>every single one of them</strong> was offered a place at university. </p>



<p>They are so impressive and they are the first in their communities to go to university. This is especially important for the girls who are breaking through traditional gender roles.</p>



<p>Now, these six students need YOUR support to be able to take up their places and earn their degrees. You can give them this life-changing opportunity for as little as $96 per month.</p>



<ul class="blocks-gallery-grid">
<li class="blocks-gallery-item">
<img src="https://childrenofconservation.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/Ndunda-Damaris-at-her-former-school-Kamunyu-Primary.-1024x768.jpg">
</li>
<li class="blocks-gallery-item">
<img src="https://childrenofconservation.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/Pascaliah-Betty-768x1024.jpg">
</li>
<li class="blocks-gallery-item">
<img src="https://childrenofconservation.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/Eric-photo-768x1024.jpeg">
</li>
<li class="blocks-gallery-item">
<img src="https://childrenofconservation.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/Photo-of-Eric-with-Samuel-SWT-community-liason-leader-1024x768.jpg">
</li>
<li class="blocks-gallery-item">
<img src="https://childrenofconservation.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/Paul-Musyoki-767x1024.jpeg">
</li>
<li class="blocks-gallery-item">
<img src="https://childrenofconservation.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/Ndunda-Damaris-with-her-mum-and-former-teachers--1024x768.jpg">
</li>
<li class="blocks-gallery-item">
<img src="https://childrenofconservation.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/elephant-2923917_1920-1024x683.jpg">
</li>
</ul>



<p>The students have taken the opportunity YOU gave them and have grasped it with both hands!<br>
<br>Now we need your help to cover the costs for their first year in university. Their fees are not high, relative to education costs here, but for their families it is an unmanageable amount of money.</p>



<p>Can you sign up as a sponsor for one of these incredible, hard-working young people? Sponsors will receive personal communication from their student, along with updates on their progress in school and a photograph.</p>



<a href="https://childrenofconservation.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/Kenya-Sponsorship-Array-including-Kelvin-scaled.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">
<img src="https://childrenofconservation.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/Kenya-Sponsorship-Array-including-Kelvin-1024x390.jpg">
</a>



<p>If you’d prefer to sponsor a student in increments, we offer the opportunity to make a monthly payment towards their education. Here are the monthly payments for each student:</p>



<a href="https://childrenofconservation.z2systems.com/np/clients/childrenofconservation/donation.jsp?campaign=7&amp;">
<img src="https://childrenofconservation.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/Yellow-and-Rose-Quartz-Bordered-Reward-Chart-1024x724.jpg">
</a>



<p>Your contribution will cover their university tuition fees, accommodation, books and living costs.</p>



<p>To sponsor one of these extraordinary kids, click here:</p>




<a class="wp-block-button__link has-black-color has-text-color has-background" href="https://childrenofconservation.z2systems.com/np/clients/childrenofconservation/donation.jsp?campaign=7&amp;" style="background-color:#04bfad" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Sponsor an extraordinary student</a>




<p>Happy Holidays to you and your family! Thank you for all your support this year.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://childrenofconservation.org/give-the-gift-of-hope-this-holiday-season/">Give the Gift of Hope this Holiday Season</a> appeared first on <a href="https://childrenofconservation.org">Children of Conservation</a>.</p>]]>
</content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://childrenofconservation.org/give-the-gift-of-hope-this-holiday-season/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Protecting Mountain Gorillas in honor of Rafiki</title>
		<link>https://childrenofconservation.org/protecting-mountain-gorillas-in-honor-of-rafiki/</link>
					<comments>https://childrenofconservation.org/protecting-mountain-gorillas-in-honor-of-rafiki/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator>
<![CDATA[lorna]]>
</dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 04 Oct 2020 23:20:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category>
<![CDATA[COVID-19]]>
</category>
		<category>
<![CDATA[Uganda]]>
</category>
		<category>
<![CDATA[Uncategorized]]>
</category>
		<category>
<![CDATA[africa]]>
</category>
		<category>
<![CDATA[conservation]]>
</category>
		<category>
<![CDATA[gorilla]]>
</category>
		<category>
<![CDATA[gorillas]]>
</category>
		<category>
<![CDATA[wildlife]]>
</category>
		<category>
<![CDATA[wildlifeconservation]]>
</category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://childrenofconservation.org/?p=2320</guid>

					<description>
<![CDATA[<p>In June of this year, villagers entered Bwindi Impenetrable Forest National Park in Uganda hunting for food. They encountered one of Bwindi&#8217;s best known silverbacks, Rafiki, panicked and speared him. Rafiki died, leaving the Nkuringo group vulnerable and their future uncertain. Bwindi is home to 43% of all the world&#8217;s remaining 1000 mountain gorillas. The&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://childrenofconservation.org/protecting-mountain-gorillas-in-honor-of-rafiki/">Protecting Mountain Gorillas in honor of Rafiki</a> appeared first on <a href="https://childrenofconservation.org">Children of Conservation</a>.</p>
]]>
</description>
										<content:encoded>
<![CDATA[<a href="https://childrenofconservation.z2systems.com/donation.jsp?campaign=8&amp;" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">
<img src="https://childrenofconservation.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/Green-White-Modern-Mens-Fashion-Facebook-Cover-1024x390.png">
</a>



<p>In June of this year, villagers entered Bwindi Impenetrable Forest National Park in Uganda hunting for food. They encountered one of Bwindi’s best known silverbacks, Rafiki, panicked and speared him. Rafiki died, leaving the Nkuringo group vulnerable and their future uncertain.</p>



<p>Bwindi is home to 43% of all the world’s remaining 1000 mountain gorillas. The loss of Rafiki is enormous from a biodiversity perspective, but also a tourism and economic perspective. Tens of thousands of visitors trek into the park every year to catch a glimpse of habituated gorillas like Rafiki and his family. As a result of COVID-19, borders have been closed, hotels shuttered and treks canceled. No visitors have been to the area around the national park, normally bustling with tourists, since March. The impact on the economy of the rural areas around Bwindi has been devastating.</p>



<p>In response to the killing of Rafiki, Children of Conservation is partnering with Dr Gladys Kalema-Zikusoka, a leading primatologist and expert in Uganda’s delicate gorilla population to raise money to prevent any more deaths. Together we plan to raise funds to support communities around the park, so that villagers don’t have to hunt and endanger the gorillas. We will also fund surveillance in the park to prevent poaching, gorilla health monitoring and COVID-19 prevention.</p>



<p>You can help by donating today!</p>




<a class="wp-block-button__link" href="https://childrenofconservation.z2systems.com/donation.jsp?campaign=8&amp;" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">Donate here to protect mountain gorillas</a>




<a href="https://childrenofconservation.z2systems.com/donation.jsp?campaign=8&amp;" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">
<img src="https://childrenofconservation.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/rafiki2-1024x614.jpg">
</a>
<p>The post <a href="https://childrenofconservation.org/protecting-mountain-gorillas-in-honor-of-rafiki/">Protecting Mountain Gorillas in honor of Rafiki</a> appeared first on <a href="https://childrenofconservation.org">Children of Conservation</a>.</p>]]>
</content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://childrenofconservation.org/protecting-mountain-gorillas-in-honor-of-rafiki/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Celebrating Success</title>
		<link>https://childrenofconservation.org/celebrating-success/</link>
					<comments>https://childrenofconservation.org/celebrating-success/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator>
<![CDATA[lorna]]>
</dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2020 18:21:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category>
<![CDATA[Kenya]]>
</category>
		<category>
<![CDATA[Uncategorized]]>
</category>
		<category>
<![CDATA[education]]>
</category>
		<category>
<![CDATA[elephantprotection]]>
</category>
		<category>
<![CDATA[scholarships]]>
</category>
		<category>
<![CDATA[sponsor]]>
</category>
		<category>
<![CDATA[sponsorship]]>
</category>
		<category>
<![CDATA[students]]>
</category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://childrenofconservation.org/?p=2318</guid>

					<description>
<![CDATA[<p>Six Kenyan teenagers have been part of pilot program between Children of Conservation and Sheldrick Wildlife Trust. In exchange for agreements from their village leaders that no more elephants will be killed, we&#8217;ve been providing scholarships for their brightest kids to go to the best school in their region. The six students all graduated high&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://childrenofconservation.org/celebrating-success/">Celebrating Success</a> appeared first on <a href="https://childrenofconservation.org">Children of Conservation</a>.</p>
]]>
</description>
										<content:encoded>
<![CDATA[<p class="has-black-color has-text-color">Six Kenyan teenagers have been part of pilot program between Children of Conservation and Sheldrick Wildlife Trust. In exchange for agreements from their village leaders that no more elephants will be killed, we’ve been providing scholarships for their brightest kids to go to the best school in their region. The six students all graduated high school earlier this summer and we are so proud to announce that <span style="text-decoration: underline;">every one of them</span> has been offered a place at university!<br>For these young people, from very impoverished rural communities, they are the first in their family to go to university. </p>



<ul class="blocks-gallery-grid">
<li class="blocks-gallery-item">
<img src="https://childrenofconservation.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/Matundu-Musyoki-at-his-former-school-Ngiluni-Primary-with-his-mother-and-former-teacher-1024x768.jpg">
</li>
<li class="blocks-gallery-item">
<img src="https://childrenofconservation.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/Ndunda-Damaris-with-her-mum-and-former-teachers--1024x768.jpg">
</li>
<li class="blocks-gallery-item">
<img src="https://childrenofconservation.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/Ndunda-Damaris-at-her-former-school-Kamunyu-Primary.-1024x768.jpg">
</li>
<li class="blocks-gallery-item">
<img src="https://childrenofconservation.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/Photo-of-Eric-with-Samuel-SWT-community-liason-leader-1024x768.jpg">
</li>
<li class="blocks-gallery-item">
<img src="https://childrenofconservation.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/Pascaliah-Betty-768x1024.jpg">
</li>
<li class="blocks-gallery-item">
<img src="https://childrenofconservation.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/IMG_6693-1024x1024.jpg">
</li>
</ul>These students, from impoverished communities, need your help to go to university this Fall.



<p class="has-black-color has-text-color">We are also so proud of the range of degrees they are studying for, from business management to environmental engineering to conservation and wildlife management.<br>The students have taken the opportunity we gave them and have grasped it with both hands!<br>
<br>Now we need your help to cover the costs for their first year in University. Their fees are not high, relative to education costs here, but for their families it is an unmanageable amount of money.</p>



<p>Can you sign up as a sponsor for one of these incredible, hard-working young people? Sponsors will receive personal communication from their student, along with updates on their progress in school and a photograph.</p>



<a href="https://childrenofconservation.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/Kenya-Sponsorship-Array-including-Kelvin-scaled.jpg">
<img src="https://childrenofconservation.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/Kenya-Sponsorship-Array-including-Kelvin-1024x390.jpg">
</a>



<a href="https://childrenofconservation.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/Kenya-Sponsorship-Array-including-Kelvin-scaled.jpg" class="wp-block-file__button" download="">Download</a>



<p>If you’d prefer to sponsor a student in increments, we offer the opportunity to make a monthly payment towards their education. Here are the monthly payments for each student:</p>



<a href="https://childrenofconservation.z2systems.com/donation.jsp?campaign=7&amp;">
<img src="https://childrenofconservation.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/09/Yellow-and-Rose-Quartz-Bordered-Reward-Chart-1024x724.jpg">
</a>



<p>Your contribution will cover their university tuition fees, accommodation, books and living costs.</p>



<p>To sponsor one of these extraordinary kids, click here:</p>




<a class="wp-block-button__link has-background" href="https://childrenofconservation.z2systems.com/donation.jsp?campaign=7&amp;" style="border-radius:1px;background-color:#04bfad">SPONSOR AN EXTRAORDINARY STUDENT</a>




<p>
</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://childrenofconservation.org/celebrating-success/">Celebrating Success</a> appeared first on <a href="https://childrenofconservation.org">Children of Conservation</a>.</p>]]>
</content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>https://childrenofconservation.org/celebrating-success/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Sanitation Stations during COVID-19 crisis</title>
		<link>https://childrenofconservation.org/sanitation-stations-during-covid-19-crisis/</link>
		
		<dc:creator>
<![CDATA[lorna]]>
</dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 01:11:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category>
<![CDATA[COVID-19]]>
</category>
		<category>
<![CDATA[Uganda]]>
</category>
		<category>
<![CDATA[covid-19]]>
</category>
		<category>
<![CDATA[sanitation]]>
</category>
		<category>
<![CDATA[WASH]]>
</category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://childrenofconservation.org/?p=1889</guid>

					<description>
<![CDATA[<p>We’ve been busy during lockdown! We have been providing&#160;sanitation stations&#160;to villages in Uganda to help suppress the spread of COVID-19. These foot-operated handwashing stations will allow people to wash their hands and prevent the spread of coronavirus and other infectious diseases. Our key supporters raised enough money to provide 40 sanitation stations to communities in&#8230;</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://childrenofconservation.org/sanitation-stations-during-covid-19-crisis/">Sanitation Stations during COVID-19 crisis</a> appeared first on <a href="https://childrenofconservation.org">Children of Conservation</a>.</p>
]]>
</description>
										<content:encoded>
<![CDATA[<video controls="" src="https://childrenofconservation.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/Sanitation-Station.mp4">
</video>



<p>
</p>



<p>We’ve been busy during lockdown!</p>



<p>We have been providing&nbsp;<strong>sanitation stations</strong>&nbsp;to villages in Uganda to help suppress the spread of COVID-19.</p>



<p>These foot-operated handwashing stations will allow people to wash their hands and prevent the spread of coronavirus and other infectious diseases.</p>



<p>
</p>



<ul class="blocks-gallery-grid">
<li class="blocks-gallery-item">
<img src="https://childrenofconservation.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/7d0329b1-430b-473d-bf68-83ab8afae678-300x169.jpg">
</li>
<li class="blocks-gallery-item">
<img src="https://childrenofconservation.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/aa94f4f9-fa33-4789-8ccc-8609836adc51-1024x606.jpg">
</li>
<li class="blocks-gallery-item">
<img src="https://childrenofconservation.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/485514bb-8fdb-4a06-9867-78d9c57a37e8-285x300.jpg">
</li>
<li class="blocks-gallery-item">
<img src="https://childrenofconservation.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/66be1abe-f891-4f55-abfe-1aa5007f3d1c-289x300.jpg">
</li>
<li class="blocks-gallery-item">
<img src="https://childrenofconservation.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/4f05e0a5-04db-4dfb-a683-2576505e812b-237x300.jpg">
</li>
<li class="blocks-gallery-item">
<img src="https://childrenofconservation.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/1da75edb-a898-4509-8988-a0c7a54f044a-912x1024.jpg">
</li>
</ul>



<p>
</p>



<p>Our key supporters raised enough money to provide 40 sanitation stations to communities in Uganda with no running water.&nbsp;<strong>Each station costs only $100.&nbsp;</strong>
</p>



<p>To everyone who contributed, we owe you a massive thank you! The tangible&nbsp;difference you are making to helping Africans fight COVID-19 is amazing.&nbsp;<strong>Thank you</strong>.&nbsp;</p>



<p>If you’d like to contribute you can&nbsp;<a href="https://childrenofconservation.z2systems.com/donation.jsp?campaign=6&amp;" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">click here</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://childrenofconservation.org/sanitation-stations-during-covid-19-crisis/">Sanitation Stations during COVID-19 crisis</a> appeared first on <a href="https://childrenofconservation.org">Children of Conservation</a>.</p>]]>
</content:encoded>
					
		
		<enclosure url="https://childrenofconservation.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/Sanitation-Station.mp4" length="3973838" type="video/mp4"/>

			</item>
		<item>
		<title>SUPPORTING AFRICA’S WILDLIFE WORKERS</title>
		<link>https://childrenofconservation.org/covid-19-crisis-in-uganda/</link>
		
		<dc:creator>
<![CDATA[lorna]]>
</dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 00:59:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category>
<![CDATA[COVID-19]]>
</category>
		<category>
<![CDATA[covid-19]]>
</category>
		<category>
<![CDATA[frontline]]>
</category>
		<category>
<![CDATA[masks]]>
</category>
		<category>
<![CDATA[Uganda]]>
</category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://childrenofconservation.org/?p=1884</guid>

					<description>
<![CDATA[<p>During the challenges Of the COVID-19 crisis, we are continuing to support frontline wildlife conservation workers and their families. We are providing hundreds of masks for wildlife workers in Uganda And need more supplies. Can You Help? Click Here to Learn More About Our Women&#8217;s Project and their mask-making during COVID-19.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://childrenofconservation.org/covid-19-crisis-in-uganda/">SUPPORTING AFRICA&#8217;S WILDLIFE WORKERS</a> appeared first on <a href="https://childrenofconservation.org">Children of Conservation</a>.</p>
]]>
</description>
										<content:encoded>
<![CDATA[<p>During the challenges Of the COVID-19 crisis, we are continuing to support frontline wildlife conservation workers and their families. We are providing hundreds of masks for wildlife workers in Uganda And need more supplies.</p>



<ul class="blocks-gallery-grid">
<li class="blocks-gallery-item">
<img src="https://childrenofconservation.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/06/PHOTO-2020-06-01-06-33-09.jpg">
</li>
<li class="blocks-gallery-item">
<img src="https://childrenofconservation.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/7e930229-8ffd-404e-bf09-b15b1e36b39c-768x1024.jpg">
</li>
<li class="blocks-gallery-item">
<img src="https://childrenofconservation.org/wp-content/uploads/2020/07/469cfd5f-371a-4075-8016-d83849e50326-1024x768.jpg">
</li>
</ul>



<p>Can You Help? Click Here to Learn More About Our Women’s Project and their mask-making during COVID-19.</p>




<a class="wp-block-button__link has-background" href="https://childrenofconservation.z2systems.com/np/clients/childrenofconservation/donation.jsp?campaign=5&amp;&amp;test=true" style="background-color:#dd890b" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">SEND MASKS TO UGANDA</a>




<p>
</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://childrenofconservation.org/covid-19-crisis-in-uganda/">SUPPORTING AFRICA’S WILDLIFE WORKERS</a> appeared first on <a href="https://childrenofconservation.org">Children of Conservation</a>.</p>]]>
</content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
